Guide to the Boswell Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- David Boswell (1640-1712), 1549-1702; Series XIV; (8 boxes)
  - LAND PURCHASES
    - Braehead
      - Disposition and sasine by Mitchell to John Mitchell, 1693 (Box 94, Folder 1723-24)
      - Sasines for James Boswell by David Boswell, 1693 (Box 94, Folder 1725-26)
  - LAND RECORDS
    - Balansholm, 1701 (Box 95, Folder 1727)
    - Bannatyne yeards, 1676 (Box 95, Folder 1727)
    - Barlonachan, 1660-63 (Box 95, Folder 1728-30)
    - Bogfoot, 1698 (Box 95, Folder 1731)
    - Craikston
      - Excambion to Quintagern Boswell of Duncanziemore, 1664-66 (Box 95, Folder 1732-38)
      - Annual rents for Laurent Charteris and Margaret Grierson, 1668-71 (Box 95, Folder 1739-41)
      - Charteris memorandum, 1672 (Box 96, Folder 1742)
      - Curatory, release and bonds by John Boswell, 1673-90 (Box 96, Folder 1743-51)
      - Clare constat and sasine for David Boswell, 1692 (Box 96, Folder 1752-53)
      - Obligations and assignations, 1692-93 (Box 96, Folder 1754-55)
      - Sasine for William Logan, 1702 (Box 96, Folder 1756)
      - Disposition by David Boswell of Auchinleck to James Boswell, 1702 (Box 96, Folder 1757)
    - Dernlaw, 1699 (Box 97, Folder 1758)
    - Dyke lands, 1701 (Box 97, Folder 1758)
    - Glensyde, 1680 (Box 97, Folder 1759)
    - Hapland, 1679-80 (Box 97, Folder 1760-61)
    - Meiklewhirr, 1699 (Box 97, Folder 1762)
    - Miln farm, 1684, 1701 (Box 97, Folder 1763)
    - Overrogerton, 1665 (Box 97, Folder 1764)
    - Thirdpart, 1687-88 (Box 97, Folder 1765)
    - Unidentified, 1690 (Box 97, Folder 1766)
  - MILITIA PAPERS
    - Commission, 1689 (Box 97, Folder 1767)
    - Receipt for muskets, 1689 (Box 97, Folder 1767)
  - PARISH RECORDS
    - Auchinleck parish
      - Account, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1768)
      - Building of aisle, 1695-1702 (Box 97, Folder 1769)
      - Contract with Rev. Allan Ramsay, 1667 (Box 97, Folder 1770)
      - Heritor's list, 1691 (Box 97, Folder 1771)
      - Horning and poinding, 1693 (Box 97, Folder 1772)
      - Patronage disposition to Cochrane of Ochiltree, 1673-95 (Box 97, Folder 1773-74)
      - Protest to the Bishop of Glasgow, 1680 (Box 97, Folder 1775)
      - Repairs to the manse of Auchinleck, 1695 (Box 97, Folder 1776)
      - Stipend claims and receipts, 1631, 1690-98 (Box 97, Folder 1777-78)
    - Mauchline parish
      - Bills and receipts, 1696-1700 (Box 97, Folder 1779)
      - Schoolmaster's accounts, 1701 (Box 97, Folder 1780)
    - Ochiltree parish
      - Reid, Alexander. A Short Account of the Lord's...Providence...from the year 1660 to the year 1693., 1770 (Box 97, Folder 1781)
    - Sorn parish
      - Receipt, 1685 (Box 97, Folder 1782)
      - Wrapper, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1783)
  - OVERSIZE
    - Charter, 1678 (Box 98, Folder 1784)
    - Sasine, 1664 (Box 98, Folder 1785)
    - Sasine of Haughdamhead by Melrose, 1555 (Box 98, Folder 1786)
    - Charter of Braehead by Melrose for Mitchell, 1555 (Box 98, Folder 1787)
    - Rental book, 1689-1707 (Box 98, Folder 1788)
- James Boswell (1672-1749), 1512-1791; Series XV; 15.5; (31 boxes)
  Series XV, James Boswell, is divided into three sections. The first, Bruce-Kincardine Papers, is organized chronologically by generation of Bruces and then alphabetically by type of material. Lady Betty Bruce Boswell, the second section, is arranged alphabetically by type of material as is the third section, James Boswell.
  - BRUCE-KINCARDINE PAPERS
    - Edward Bruce of Kinloss
      - Letters to Sir George Bruce of Carnock, 1604-10, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1789-92)
      - Submission of differences with Patrick Dunbar, 1597 (Box 99, Folder 1793)
      - Tack of salmon fishing profits, 1611 (Box 99, Folder 1794)
      - Tack of teind sheaves
    - Sir George Bruce of Carnock
      - Correspondence
        - Cavendish, -- (Box 99, Folder 1795)
        - Lumsden, Charles, 1617 (Box 99, Folder 1795)
        - Unidentified, [ca. 1690?] (Box 99, Folder 1795)
      - Personal papers
        - Bond of obligation, 1613 (Box 99, Folder 1796)
        - Commission for the Union of England and Scotland
          - "Articles...to be proponed unto the Parliaments", n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1797)
          - List of commissioners, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1798)
        - Commission to David Mitchell, 1642 (Box 99, Folder 1799)
        - Contract with David Primrose, 1621 (Box 99, Folder 1800)
        - Customs account of Culross, 1609 (Box 99, Folder 1801)
        - Discharge of debt, 1614 (Box 99, Folder 1802)
        - Precept of factorie, 1604 (Box 99, Folder 1803)
        - Tack of the teinds of Castletown, 1613 (Box 99, Folder 1804)
        - Tocher receipt of Christian Colvill, 1604 (Box 99, Folder 1805)
        - Will and testament, 1641, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1806)
    - Edward Bruce, 1st Earl of Kincardine
      - Committee of Estates, 1644 (Box 99, Folder 1807)
      - Nomination of David Mitchell as factor, 1644 (Box 99, Folder 1808)
      - Patent as Lord Elgin (photocopy), n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1809)
      - Patent draft for change of title, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1810)
      - Privy Council act on patent, 1648 (Box 99, Folder 1811)
      - "Purves paper concerning the medical condition of Edward, Earl of Kincardine" (Box 99, Folder 1812)
      - Will and testament, 1648 (Box 99, Folder 1813)
    - Alexander Bruce, 2nd Earl of Kincardine
      - Correspondence
        - Argyll, Anna Mackenzie, Countess of, 1672, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1814)
        - Argyll, Archibald Campbell, E. of, 1656-77, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1815-19)
        - [Bruce, Alexander, of Broomhall]: letterbook, 1660-80, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1820)
        - Bruce, Charles, Lord, 1672, 1678-79 (Box 100, Folder 1821)
        - Bruce family: letterbook, 1672-80 (Box 100, Folder 1822)
        - Bruce, Sir Robert, of Broomhall, 1649-50 (Box 100, Folder 1823)
        - [Burnet, Gilbert, Bp. of Salisbury]: letterbook, 1660-73, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1824)
        - Caithness, George Sinclair, E. of, 1668-73, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1825-27)
        - Cardross, Henry Erskine, B., 1676 (Box 100, Folder 1828)
        - Colden, George, 1660 (Box 100, Folder 1829)
        - Dalzell, --, 1666 (Box 100, Folder 1830)
        - Devonshire, William Cavendish, E. of, 1645-73, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1831-32)
        - Devonshire, William Cavendish, E. and 1st D. of, 1660-79 (Box 100, Folder 1833)
        - Elzevier, A. --, 1664-75, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1834)
        - [Guthry, Henry, Bp. of Dunkeld?], 1669 (Box 100, Folder 1835)
        - Hamilton, William Douglas, D. of: letterbook, 1673, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1836)
        - Henderson, --, 1649, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1837)
        - Huntly, George Gordon, M. of, 1672 (Box 100, Folder 1838)
        - Kincardine, Alexander Bruce, 2nd E. of: letterbook of drafts, 1673, 1676 (Box 100, Folder 1839)
        - [Lauderdale, Elizabeth Murray, D. of]: letterbook, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1840)
        - Lauderdale, John Maitland, D. of, 1674 (Box 100, Folder 1841)
        - Mar, Charles Erskine, E. of, 1668-77 (Box 100, Folder 1842)
        - Mar, John Erskine, E. of, 1654-57 (Box 100, Folder 1843)
        - Middleton, Charles Middleton, 2nd E. of, 1662 (Box 100, Folder 1844)
        - Perth, James Drummond, 1st D. of, 1673-79 (Box 101, Folder 1845-46)
        - Primrose, G.--, 1645 (Box 101, Folder 1847)
        - Rothes, John Leslie, D. of, 1656-75, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1848-49)
        - Sommelsdyck family: letterbook, 1659-78, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1850)
        - Stair, James Dalrymple, 1st V., [1660] (Box 101, Folder 1851)
        - Tweeddale, John Hay, 2nd E. and 1st M. of, 1662-69, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1852)
        - Wallis, Jacob, Johan, and Edouard (Box 101, Folder 1853)
        - Wemyss, David Wemyss, E. of, 1657-76, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1854-55)
        - Werden, Sir John, 1674-79 (Box 101, Folder 1856-58)
        - Wintoun, George Seton, E. of, 1668-1674 (Box 101, Folder 1859)
        - Letterbook, 1660-76, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1860)
        - Register of letters, 1672 May-Nov (Box 101, Folder 1861)
        - Unidentified letters, 1662-74, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1862)
      - Family papers
        - "Admiralty Act anent a Frenchman", 1674 (Box 101, Folder 1863)
        - Appeal against the United Presbyteries, 1693 (Box 101, Folder 1864)
        - Appointment of David Erskine as Deputy Admiral, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1865)
        - Backbond to the Lords Commissioners, 1682 (Box 101, Folder 1866)
        - Bruce arms: note, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1867)
        - Commission as Captain of Horse, 1667 (Box 101, Folder 1868)
        - Commission as Lord of Treasury, 1669
        - Commission by Lady Kincardine for Robert Andrew, 1683 (Box 101, Folder 1869)
        - Commission by Lady Kincardine for Hugh Dalrymple, 1697 (Box 101, Folder 1870)
        - "Compendium Logicum" in Kincardine's hand, 1645 (Box 101, Folder 1871)
        - Dispositions to Lady Elizabeth Bruce, 1684-1702 (Box 102, Folder 1872-75)
        - Inventories of the furnishings of Culross, 1694, 1702-04 (Box 102, Folder 1876-78)
        - Marriage contract with Veronica van Aerssen van Sommelsdyck, 1659 (Box 102, Folder 1879-81)
        - Marriage provisions
          - Charter, 1660 (Box 102, Folder 1882)
          - Sasine, 1660 (Box 102, Folder 1883)
          - Discharge of debt to Sommelsdyck, 1680 (Box 102, Folder 1884)
          - Testimony of M. de Hertogla, 1681 (Box 102, Folder 1885)
          - Account of jointure owed, 1690 (Box 102, Folder 1886)
          - "Memorial of the affairs of Kincardine", [ca. 1695] (Box 102, Folder 1887)
          - Testimony of Veronica, Countess of Kincardine, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1888)
        - Passport to Bremen, 1657 (Box 102, Folder 1889)
        - Privy Council papers
          - Appointment to the Council, 1674 (Box 102, Folder 1890)
          - "Papers relating to Scots affairs", 1660-66, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1891)
          - "Reasons...for suppresyng feild conventicles", 1675 (Box 102, Folder 1892)
        - Ratification of gift of shipwreck, 1682 (Box 102, Folder 1893)
        - Sasine, 1709 (Box 102, Folder 1894)
        - Summons before the House of Commons, 1673 (Box 103, Folder 1895)
        - Tack of the gardens of Culross, 1697 (Box 103, Folder 1896)
        - Tack of the salt excise, 1673 (Box 103, Folder 1897)
        - Tocher discharges by Sir John Cochrane, 1681-83 (Box 103, Folder 1898)
        - Warrant for Kincardine to be Earl of Forth, 1663 (Box 103, Folder 1899)
        - Wills and testaments
          - Testament of Alexander Bruce, Earl of Kincardine, 1681 (Box 103, Folder 1900)
          - Testament and codicils of Veronica, Countess of Kincardine, 1707-08 (Box 103, Folder 1901-02)
          - Will of Cornelius van Aerssen van Sommelsdyck, 1662 (Box 103, Folder 1903)
          - Will of Petronilla van Aerssen, 1609 (Box 103, Folder 1904)
    - Charles, Lord Bruce
      - Commission in the service of the States-General, 1678 (Box 103, Folder 1905)
      - Commission as captain, 1679 (Box 103, Folder 1906)
      - Letter of acceptance, 1680 (Box 103, Folder 1906)
      - Permission for a leave of absence, 1679 (Box 103, Folder 1906)
    - Alexander Bruce, 3rd Earl of Kincardine
      - Bond and discharge, 1703-04 (Box 103, Folder 1907)
      - Charter of royal pension, 1704 (Box 103, Folder 1908)
      - Creditor's agreement, 1699 (Box 103, Folder 1909)
      - Disposition of estate to William Cochrane of Ochiltree, 1703 (Box 103, Folder 1910)
      - Letter on the death of Lord George Douglas, 1693 (Box 103, Folder 1911)
      - Wrappers, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 1912-13)
  - LADY BETTY BRUCE BOSWELL
    - Correspondence
      - Auverquerque, Frances van Aerssen van Sommelsdyck, Lady: letterbook, 1697-1717, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1914)
      - Boswell, Alexander, 1734 (Box 104, Folder 1915)
      - Bruce, Andrew, 1731, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1916)
      - Cochrane, Mary Bruce, Lady: letterbook, 1707-33, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1917)
      - Mair, Rev. George: letterbook, 1702-15, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1918)
      - Monro, Rev. George: letterbook, 1695-99 (Box 104, Folder 1919)
      - Murray, Anne Bruce, Lady: letterbook, 1698-1721 (Box 104, Folder 1920)
    - Devotional literature
      - Aird, Rev. James: manuscripts in his hand, 1692-97, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 1921)
      - "Derniers heures de feu. Monsieur Follyvet, 1662", n.d. (Box 105, Folder 1922)
      - Discourse on Romans 6:17, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 1923)
      - Sermons and meditations, 1710, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 1924)
      - Miscellany in Lady Boswell's hand, 1702, 1710, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 1925)
      - Miscellany, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 1926)
      - Miscellany, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 1927)
      - Miscellany, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 1928)
    - Personal papers
      - Assignation to Sir David Murray of Stanhope, 1704 (Box 106, Folder 1929)
      - Contracts with William Cochrane of Ochiltree, 1703-04 (Box 106, Folder 1930-32)
      - Declaration on deeds of grant (Box 106, Folder 1933)
      - Inhibition against Col. John Erskine, 1713 (Box 106, Folder 1934)
      - Inventories, 1702, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1935)
      - Memorial of financial settlement, 1698 (Box 106, Folder 1936)
  - JAMES BOSWELL
    - Barony records
      - Dispositions, 1718-34 (Box 107, Folder 1937)
    - Burgess tickets
      - Glasgow, 1708 (Box 107, Folder 1938)
      - Mauchline, 1700 (Box 107, Folder 1939)
    - Estate papers
      - Accounts
        - Household, 1708-11 (Box 107, Folder 1940)
        - Meal and corn, 1723-33 (Box 107, Folder 1941-42)
        - Money, 1723-33, 1744 (Box 107, Folder 1943)
      - Barony court book, 1715-91 (Box 107, Folder 1944)
      - Notes on estate, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 1945)
      - Rental book, 1705-14 (Box 107, Folder 1946)
      - Rental book, 1716-27 (Box 108, Folder 1947)
      - Rental book, 1727-37 (Box 108, Folder 1948)
      - Rental book, 1730-36 (Box 108, Folder 1949)
      - Rental book, 1737-42 (Box 108, Folder 1950)
      - Rental book, 1736-48 (Box 109, Folder 1951)
      - Rental book, 1748-51 (Box 109, Folder 1952)
      - Rental statement, 1737 (Box 109, Folder 1953)
      - "Rentals of Auchinleck barony", 1742 (Box 109, Folder 1954)
      - Sale of woods, 1744 (Box 109, Folder 1955)
      - Tenants' submission of differences, 1715 (Box 109, Folder 1956)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 1957)
    - Family papers
      - Apprenticeship agreements
        - James Boswell, 1690 (Box 109, Folder 1958)
        - John Boswell, 1727 (Box 109, Folder 1959)
      - Certificate of study, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 1960)
      - Correspondence
        - Abercrombie, Thomas, 1738 (Box 109, Folder 1961)
        - Alexander, A., 1735 (Box 109, Folder 1961)
        - Ainsley, Walter, 1775 (Box 109, Folder 1961)
        - Andrews, Thomas, 1731 (Box 109, Folder 1961)
        - Boghead, --, 1734 (Box 109, Folder 1962)
        - Boswell, Alexander, 1734 (Box 109, Folder 1962)
        - Boswell, James, 1742 (Box 109, Folder 1962)
        - Boswell, John, 1735 (Box 109, Folder 1962)
        - Brown, Robert, 1733 (Box 109, Folder 1962)
        - Cochrane, Charles, 1713 (Box 109, Folder 1963)
        - Cochrane, John, 1735-36 (Box 109, Folder 1963)
        - Crawford, Andrew, 1732 (Box 109, Folder 1963)
        - Crawford, David, 1732 (Box 109, Folder 1963)
        - Cunningham, James, 1733 (Box 109, Folder 1963)
        - Gairdner, John, 1732 (Box 109, Folder 1964)
        - Gillespie, John, 1732 (Box 109, Folder 1964)
        - Gordon, James (Box 109, Folder 1964)
        - Hamilton, Sir David: letterbook, 1697-1721 (Box 109, Folder 1965)
        - Hunter, Andrew, 1732 (Box 110, Folder 1966)
        - Hunter, James, 1731-32 (Box 110, Folder 1966)
        - Lindsay, Montgomerie, 1731 (Box 110, Folder 1967)
        - Lowrie, John, 1695-1705 (Box 110, Folder 1967)
        - McLinnoe, Thomas, 1735 (Box 110, Folder 1968)
        - Maitland, W.-- (Box 110, Folder 1968)
        - Montgomerie, Robert, 1736 (Box 110, Folder 1968)
        - Montgomerie, Veronica Boswell
          See: Series II, Box 28, folder 690
        - Paterson, Robert, 1736-37 (Box 110, Folder 1969)
        - Reid, George, 1735 (Box 110, Folder 1970)
        - Robertsone, William, 1735 (Box 110, Folder 1970)
        - Rodger, Hugh, 1733-36 (Box 110, Folder 1970)
        - Samson, George, 1733 (Box 110, Folder 1971)
        - Scott, J.--, 1726 (Box 110, Folder 1971)
        - Unidentified, 1721-37 (Box 110, Folder 1972)
      - Financial papers
        Accounts and discharges
        See also: Series II, Box 14, folder 332
        - Alexander Boswell, 1737, 1743 (Box 110, Folder 1973)
        - James Boswell, 1727-46 (Box 110, Folder 1974)
        - John Boswell, 1742 (Box 110, Folder 1975)
        - Bills and receipts, 1699-1726, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 1976)
        - Cess receipts, 1735-37 (Box 110, Folder 1977)
        - Debt accounts, 1704-43 (Box 110, Folder 1978-79)
        - Debt of William Dick, 1730-36 (Box 110, Folder 1980)
        - Debt of John Reid, 1737 (Box 110, Folder 1981)
        - Debt of John Sampson, 1735-36 (Box 110, Folder 1982)
        - Debts of Lord Torpichen and Andrew Marjoribanks, 1728-42, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 1983-89)
        - "Kincardine finances", n.d. (Box 110, Folder 1990)
        - Payment orders, 1715-47, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 1991-92)
      - Genealogical material
        - Bethune family, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 1993)
        - Boswell family, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 1994)
          See also: Box 17, folder 380
      - Inventories
        - Dressing plate, 1739 (Box 110, Folder 1995)
      - Marriage contracts and provisions
        Ann Boswell and George Campbell
        - Contract, 1708 (Box 110, Folder 1996)
        - Provisions, 1710-48 (Box 110, Folder 1997)
        - James Boswell and Lady Elizabeth Bruce
          - Contracts, 1704-10 (Box 111, Folder 1998-99)
          - Assignations, 1704 (Box 111, Folder 2000)
          - Dispositions, 1704 (Box 111, Folder 2001-02)
          - Obligations, 1704 (Box 111, Folder 2003)
          - Resignation, 1704 (Box 111, Folder 2004)
        - Jean Boswell and Lieutenant John Campbell
          - Contract, 1697 (Box 111, Folder 2005)
        - Margaret Boswell and Hugh Campbell of Balquharrie
          - Contract, 1702 (Box 111, Folder 2006)
          - Discharge of obligation, 1719 (Box 111, Folder 2007)
      - Minutes, 1734 (Box 111, Folder 2008)
      - Petitions: Admission to the Bar, 1696 (Box 111, Folder 2009)
      - Testaments
        - Testament dative qua creditor, 1750 (Box 111, Folder 2010)
        - Testament of Ann Monroe, 1746 (Box 111, Folder 2011)
        - Testamentary view of the estate, 1750 (Box 111, Folder 2012)
    - Land purchases
      - Auchtintinch
        - Inventories of the writs, 1731, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2013-14)
        - Progress of the writs
          - Charter for William Wallace of Craigie, 1512 (Box 111, Folder 2015)
          - Clare constat and sasine for Hugh Wallace of Craigie, 1564-67 (Box 111, Folder 2016)
          - Sasine for Reids, 1567 (Box 111, Folder 2017)
          - Renunciation by Cowran of half mark land for Reid, 1581 (Box 111, Folder 2018)
          - Sasine for Andrew Reid, 1591 (Box 111, Folder 2019)
          - Sasine by Andrew Reid for Patrick Hamilton, 1600 (Box 111, Folder 2020)
          - Charter and sasine by Andrew Reid for William Reid, 1600-01 (Box 111, Folder 2021-22)
          - Reid for William Campbell, 1602 (Box 111, Folder 2023)
          - William C. charter for Charles Campbell, 1606 (Box 112, Folder 2024)
          - Campbell and Cunningham charters and sasines, 1627-47 (Box 112, Folder 2025-30)
          - Dispositions by Campbell to Robert Creighton, 1659-63 (Box 112, Folder 2031-35)
          - Disposition to Charles Crichton, 1705-07 (Box 112, Folder 2036-39)
        - Heritable bonds (debts?) to Charles Duncan and George Vallance, 1709 (Box 112, Folder 2040-43)
        - Disposition to John Gillespie, 1709 (Box 112, Folder 2044)
        - Charter and sasine--Gillespie, 1724-29 (Box 112, Folder 2045-46)
        - Disposition to James Boswell, 1731 (Box 112, Folder 2047)
      - Drumfork and Ballangape
        - Inventory of the writs by Melrose, 1714 (Box 113, Folder 2048)
        - Progress of the writs
          - Papal confirmation, charter, and sasine for Mungo Reid, 1556-63 (Box 113, Folder 2049)
          - Clare constat and sasine for Quintagern (Mungo) Reid, 1582 (Box 113, Folder 2050)
          - Retour and sasine for Mungo Reid, 1636 (Box 113, Folder 2051)
          - Life-rent of income to Isobell Boswell, 1636 (Box 113, Folder 2052)
          - Sale by M. Reid?? Disposition to Charles Dalrymple, 1649-50 (Box 113, Folder 2053-55)
          - Renunciation by George and William Campbell, 1650 (Box 113, Folder 2056)
          - Bonds to Elizabeth Campbell (Hugh Dunbar), 1657 (Box 113, Folder 2057-58)
          - Suits for debt, 1658-64 (Box 113, Folder 2059-62)
          - Assignations of debt, 1669 (Box 113, Folder 2063-64)
          - Disposition to Andrew Dalrymple, 1669 (Box 114, Folder 2065)
          - Suits for debt, 1673-78 (Box 114, Folder 2066-69)
          - Marriage contract: Margaret Dalrymple and Adam Aird of Catrine, 1687 (Box 114, Folder 2070)
          - Inheritance of Margaret Dalrymple, 1688 (Box 114, Folder 2071-73)
          - A. Suits for debt, 1710 (Box 114, Folder 2074)
          - Tacks of Drumfork by Aird, 1710-12 (Box 114, Folder 2075)
          - Suit for debt, 1712 (Box 114, Folder 2076)
          - Tacks, 1713 (Box 114, Folder 2077)
        - Sale to James Boswell, 1713-18, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2078-84)
        - Wrappers, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2085)
      - Heitath
        - Wadset, 1601 (Box 115, Folder 2086)
        - Tack by Boswell for Mirrie, 1718 (Box 115, Folder 2087)
        - Minute of sale, 1730 (Box 115, Folder 2088)
      - Howieson purchase
        - Accounts from debtor's prison, 1723, 1730 (Box 115, Folder 2089)
        - Correspondence, 1726-30 (Box 115, Folder 2090)
        - Progress of the writs by Melrose
          - Disposition to John Manson, 1545-46 (Box 115, Folder 2091-92)
          - Bonds and suits for debt, 1680-95 (Box 115, Folder 2093-2103)
          - Sasine for George Hudd, 1704 (Box 115, Folder 2104)
          - Sasines for Richard Howieson, 1705-09 (Box 115, Folder 2105-07)
          - Contract with the Earl of Loudoun, 1713 (Box 115, Folder 2108)
          - Clare constat and sasine for Archibald Nisbit, 1715 (Box 116, Folder 2109)
          - Disposition by Nisbit to Howieson, 1719 (Box 116, Folder 2110)
          - Suits for debt, 1724-25 (Box 116, Folder 2111-12)
          - Tacks, 1726-27 (Box 116, Folder 2113-14)
          - Sale to James Boswell, 1730-37 (Box 116, Folder 2115-20)
          - Title clearances, 1740-47 (Box 116, Folder 2121-25)
        - Receipts, 1728-38 (Box 116, Folder 2126)
        - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2127)
      - Kingzeancleuch (Willockston)
        Progress of the writs
        Charters for Robert Campbell
        - Suits for debt against Robert Campbell, 1714-25 (Box 116, Folder 2128-30)
        - Sale to James Boswell, 1725-27, 1736 (Box 116, Folder 2131-34)
      - Lindsayhill and Logan
        - Inventory of the writs (Box 117, Folder 2135-36)
        - Progress of the writs
          Charter to John Mitchell of Logan
          - Sasine by Melrose for Robert Wilson of Lindsayhill, 1555 (Box 117, Folder 2137)
          - Confirmation of the rights of Logan to John Smith
          - Confirmation by Papal Commission for Robert Wilson, 1557 (Box 117, Folder 2138)
          - Charter and disposition for Robert Wilson, 1581, 1587 (Box 117, Folder 2139-40)
          - Charters and sasine for John Wilson, 1623, 1625 (Box 117, Folder 2141-42)
          - Inheritance progress of John Wilson, 1673-74 (Box 117, Folder 2143-44)